Gaurav Arora Anaheim, CA

Executive Summary:

Highly educated working professional with financial, analytical, and reporting experience, working crossfunctionally with all levels of engineering, project management, business intelligence, and both corporate and global finance driving profitable results. Expert cost/financial skills and pursuing CPA certification.

Software:

SAP, Crystal Reports, Concur, Oracle, Hyperion, MS Excel, Word, Access, PowerPoint, QuickBooks Enterprise, Business Objects, Deltek, PeopleSoft, NetSuite, MS Dynamics, Epicor, Tableau, Cognos, Syteline, PowerBl

Employment History:

Aerospace Consulting, El Segundo, CA (Contract) - \$1 Billion Division April 2018-Present Cost Accountant - Clients include Raytheon/Lockheed Martin (Product Manufacturing)

- Drive the creation of \$1B company budgets and forecasts throughout the year; maintain and develop various Excel-based financial models and standard templates for variances; consolidate, analyze, and summarize global overhead and benchmarking against the plan, forecasts, and prior results to management (Income Statement, Balance Sheet, and Trial Balance) for IFRS/GAAP using SAP HANA, Tableau, PowerBI, Syteline
- Perform/oversee activities related to cost accounting general ledger activities from monthly journal entries through trial balance analysis, monthly analysis of COGS and gross margin results in metric and narrative form, manufacturing variance analysis, collect data for percentage completion, fixed assets, inventory activity
- Assist operations and management on special projects and possess the ability to lead meetings cross functionally to deliver financial analytic results and provide recommendations, work integrally with all functional areas in the company to understand costs and variances to assist in providing detailed analysis related to COGS, R&D expenses/capitalization, labor/overhead/materials, SOX audits, bank reconciliation, dashboards
- Work closely with the materials and warehouse departments to ensure appropriate product costing and conduct audit activities to ensure accurate cycle counts and physical inventory valuations, weekly flash reports and operational metrics, reconcile inventory transactions related to perpetual inventory (RM, WIP, FG) and prepare journal entries to reflect these transactions on a monthly basis, reconcile inventory transactions related to demo and field inventory and prepare journal entries to reflect these transactions on a monthly basis, update master data records for standard cost/absorption, special/ad-hoc projects as requested, research cost data generated from SAP COPA module and AR/AP including allocated P&L by channel/series, bill of material updates, intercompany reporting, ROI/KPI's using JDE Enterprise/Sage/SQL and ASC 606

Northrop Grumman, El Segundo, CA (Contract) - \$1 Billion Division January 2016-January 2018 Cost Accountant - for teams of 5-10 (Space/Aircraft Division Product Manufacturing)

- Drive the creation of \$1B company budgets and forecasts throughout the year; maintain and develop various Excel-based financial models and standard templates; consolidate, analyze, and summarize global overhead results against the plan, forecasts, and prior results to management (Income Statement, Balance Sheet, and Trial Balance) for reports to summarize KPI results for IFRS/GAAP using SAP, Sage, Hyperion, Epicor, SQL
- Perform/oversee activities related to cost accounting general ledger activities from monthly journal entries through trial balance analysis, monthly analysis of COGS and gross margin results in metric and narrative form, manufacturing variance analysis, collect data for product cost analysis, fixed assets, inventory activity
- Assist operations and management on special projects and possess the ability to lead meetings cross functionally to deliver financial analytic results and provide recommendations, work integrally with all functional areas in the company to understand costs and variances to assist in providing detailed analysis related to COGS, operating expenses and financial results, labor/overhead/materials, assist with SOX external audits
- Work closely with the materials and warehouse departments to ensure appropriate product costing and conduct audit activities to ensure accurate cycle counts and physical inventory valuations, weekly flash reports and operational metrics, reviewing the work-in-process batches for financial accuracy including reviewing the material job issues, BOM implosions, cost updates, weekly sub-ledger balance postings and GL postings,

partnering with warehouse/inventory control on weekly inventory cycle counts and physical inventories, work closely with supply chain on reduction of aged and obsolete inventory, estimate inventory reserve requirement

Boeing, Huntington Beach, CA & Seattle, WA - \$10 Billion Division March 2014-October 2015 Financial/Cost Accounting Analyst - Operations/Engineering (Aircraft, implemented PeopleSoft)

- Ensured financial records including the general ledger were maintained in compliance with GAAP principles, International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS); managed the company's cash position, monitored cycle counting, physical inventory counts, lead and managed the quarterly excess and worked with R&D to price out new item requests for KPI's using PeopleSoft Financials, Cognos, Tableau, Quickbooks, Great Plains
- Managed the month end close duties including manufacturing variances, E&O, and absorption; analyzed and
 reported on manufacturing costs and variances on weekly basis, address both domestic and international cost
 related topics to include items such as product development costs, duty costs, packaging and labeling

Education:

Argosy University

Master of Business Administration (concentration in Finance and Accounting), GPA: 3.80

California State University Fullerton

Bachelor's in Business Administration (concentration in Finance and Accounting), GPA: 3.50